Guide to the N. Scott Momaday Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Papers, 1788-2012; 1950s-2012
  - "Futures 9/29-30, Santa Fe", 2006 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence and materials re: Futures for Children Conference, Santa Fe, NM (2006)
  - "Thanksgiving & CLE 2006" (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence and travel materials re: CLE at Sea Caribbean cruise
  - "NSM Pending", 2005-06 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence and materials re: miscellaneous project proposals
  - "Misc. Publisher & Agency", 2004-06 (Box 91)
    One folder of miscellaneous publisher correspondence and royalty statements
  - "Misc. Corresp. & Invites--NSM 2005 & 2006", 2005-06 (Box 91)
    One folder of miscellaneous business correspondence (2005-06)
  - "Permissions 2006" (Box 91)
    One small folder of publisher permissions (2006)
  - "Permissions 2005" (Box 91)
    One large folder of publisher permissions (2005)
  - "NSM--Quotes & Blurbs", 1998-2005 (Box 91)
    One small folder of miscellaneous quotes and blurbs by NSM
  - "St. Johns 2006" (Box 91)
    One small folder of miscellaneous correspondence w/ St. Johns College
  - "Greenfield", 2005 (Box 91)
    One small folder of miscellaneous correspondence w/ Stewart H. Greenfield
  - "Gaetano", 2004 (Box 91)
    One small folder of miscellaneous correspondence w/ "Gaetano and Clara"
  - "Olivier", 2005 (Box 91)
    One small folder of miscellaneous correspondence w/ Olivier Delavault
  - "Betsy & Ted Rogers", 2005 (Box 91)
    One small folder of miscellaneous correspondence w/ Betsy & Ted Rogers, plus issue of SITELINES
  - "Stewart Udall", 2005 (Box 91)
    One small folder of business materials re: Stewart Udall Environmental Award
  - "Foote/Feinberg/Dobkins", 2005 (Box 91)
    One small folder of business correspondence re: Jemez and Indian Market
  - "Venice, FL High School", 2006 (Box 91)
    One small folder of business correspondence re: Venice, Fl High School talk
  - "O'Keeffe", 2006 (Box 91)
    One small folder of business correspondence re: Georgia O'Keeffe Museum
  - "McCune 10/20", 2006 (Box 91)
    One small folder of business correspondence re: McCune Charitable Foundation
  - MISCELLANEOUS, 2001-02 (Box 91)
    One small folder of miscellaneous business correspondence and organizational materials
  - "Natachee Momaday" (1), 1992-94 (Box 92)
    One small folder of miscellaneous business receipts and correspondence re: Natachee Momaday (mother)
  - "Natachee Momaday" (2), 1994-95 (Box 92)
    One large group of health insurance and Medicaid/Medicare papers re: Natachee Momaday (mother)
  - "Natachee Momaday" (3), 1995-97 (Box 92)
    One large group of bank statements re: Natachee Momaday (mother)
  - "Natachee Momaday" (4), 1992-95 (Box 92)
    One large group of bank statements and income tax returns re: Natachee Momaday (mother)
  - "Natachee Momaday" (5), 1995 (Box 92)
    One group of bank statements and income tax returns re: Natachee Momaday (mother)
  - "Natachee Momaday" (6), 1992-95 (Box 92)
    One group of legal papers (Will and General Power of Attorney) re: Natachee Momaday (mother)
  - "Sandra Tedlock" (1), 1994-95 (Box 92)
    One folder of legal materials and divorce/dissolution papers re: Atty. Sandra Tedlock
  - "Sandra Tedlock" (2), 1994-95 (Box 92)
  - "Sandra Tedlock" (3), 1994 (Box 92)
    One folder of legal materials, correspondence and divorce/dissolution papers re: Atty. Sandra Tedlock
  - "NSM Taxes/Past Tax Returns/1988-94" (Box 92)
    One large folder of tax returns and financial papers re: NSM (1988-1994)
  - "NSM Taxes 1995" (Box 92)
    One folder of tax returns and financial papers re: NSM (1995)
  - "NSM Income/Credit Card Statements/Bank Statements 1995" (Box 92)
    One large group of bank statements and financial papers re: NSM (1995)
  - "NSM Receipts 1995" (Box 92)
    One folder of receipts re: NSM (1995)
  - "Man Made of Words" (1), 1996 (Box 93)
    MSS: "Man Made of Words": one large group of typescripts and offprints of the essays that would become the finished book, from "The Arrowmaker" to "Dreaming in Place"
  - "Man Made of Words" (2), 1996 (Box 93)
    MSS: "Man Made of Words": another large group of typescripts and offprints of the essays that would become the finished book
  - "Native Voice in American Literature", 1996 (Box 93)
    MSS: "Native Voice in American Literature": multiple copies of this essay
  - "The Centaur Complex", 1996 (Box 93)
    MSS: "The Centaur Complex": multiple copies of this essay
  - "Man Made of Words" (3), 1996 (Box 93)
    MSS: "Man Made of Words": introduction and publisher correspondence
  - "Man Made of Words" (4), 1996 (Box 93)
    MSS: "Man Made of Words": one folder of misc. essays
  - "Man Made of Words" (5), 1996 (Box 93)
    MSS: "Man Made of Words": one folder of outlines and lists
  - "Man Made of Words" (6), 1996 (Box 93)
    MSS: "Man Made of Words": one folder of "extra/edited sheets" of various essays
  - NOTEBOOK (1): AL & NATACHEE MOMADAY, 1940s-80s (Box 94)
    One large black ringbound notebook with 85 8"x10" B&W photographs, plus numerous smaller B&W photos documenting the lives and activities of N. Scott Momaday's parents, artists Al and Natachee Momaday (1940s-80s). Includes various posed and unposed photographs of Al and Natachee Momaday. Also includes photos of both N. Scott and Al Momaday receiving joint Honorary Documents at Lawrence University; photos of President Harry S. Truman receiving a Native American belt from Vidal Cosiquinto (1952) and overseeing a Children's Art Contest (1951); numerous photos re: life at the Jemez Day School where Al Momaday was Principal and teacher (most 1960s); a Native American parade in which N. Scott Momaday was honored; A Native American beauty pageant at an Annual Arts & Crafts Exposition and Pow Wow (1968); shots of the first Indian and Western Artifact Show undated; The Momadays working on a mural; early (1960s) images of N. Scott Momaday, including graduation; a great shot of N. Scott Momaday in full headdress receiving the 1969 American Outstanding Indian Citizen's Award in Anadarko, OK; plus later images of Natachee Momaday and contact sheets
  - PHOTOS BY N. SCOTT MOMADAY (1), [1960s] (Box 94)
    One large black ringbound notebook with 38 8"x10" B&W photographs mounted on heavy cardboard, presumably taken by N. Scott Momaday of his first wife Gael; his children; Natachee Momaday; Al Momaday; et. al.
  - PHOTOS BY N. SCOTT MOMADAY (2), [1990s] (Box 94)
    One large black ringbound notebook with 33 8"x10" full-color digital prints, presumably taken by N. Scott Momaday of his father's death mask; Southwest landscapes and architecture; Soviet Union; Native American festivals and attire; petroglyphs; et. al. plus a shot of his Leicaflex camera
  - PHOTOS BY N. SCOTT MOMADAY (3), [1990s] (Box 94)
    One large black ringbound notebook with 28 8"x10" full-color digital prints of N. Scott Momaday and Barbara Glenn and family (children, grandchildren, et. al.)
  - VINTAGE NATIVE AMERICAN PHOTOGRAPHS, (1940s-60s) (Box 94)
    One large black ringbound notebook with 56 original 8"x10" B&W photographs documenting Southwest Native American life: architecture, art, handicrafts, tribal attire, landscapes, pueblos, Jemez Day School, et. al. (1940s-80s)
  - AUTHOR PHOTOGRAPHS, undated (Box 94)
    One small black ringbound notebook with original 8"x10" B&W and photographs of N. Scott Momaday
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (1): "Jemez Day School", 1996 (Box 95)
    One group of 25 color prints re: the Jemez Day School in 1996 (abandoned buildings) w/ negatives
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (2): "Buffalo Trust", 2005 (Box 95)
    Two large groups of 100+ color prints re: Buffalo Trust dinner and Siberian delegation, Santa Fe NM, March-April, 2005 w/ note from Susan Scarberry-Garcia
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (3): "NSM Family Photos" (1), 2004 (Box 95)
    CD-ROM: One full disc of numerous rolls of N. Scott Momaday's photographs (landscapes, Barbara Glenn, et. al) (~1000 images), 8/21/04
    CD-R removed to Box 106.
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (4): "Anna", 2002 (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~60 B&W photos of "Anna" on a beach in France, 5/22/02 (w/ negatives)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (5): "Siberia" (1), 2004 (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS and CD-ROM: One set of ~60 color photos of Siberia, 9/28/04
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (6): "Petroglyphs", 2004 (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~70 color photos of Southwest desert petroglyph excursion w/ Barbara Glenn (2004)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (7): "NSM and Family" (1), 2004 (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~70 color photos re: NSM, Barbara, baby photos etc.
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (8): "Siberia" (2), 2004 (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~70 color photos of Siberia, 9/28/04
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (9): "Siberia" (3), 2004 (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~70 color photos of Siberia and Southwest desert petroglyphs, 9/28/04
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (10): "NSM and Family" (2), 2004 (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS and CD-ROM: One set of ~115 color photos of NSM, Barbara, friends and family (11-23-04)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (11): "Paris" (1), 2002 (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~750 color photos and negatives re: Paris (5/22/02)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (12): "Siberia" (4), 2004 (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of 21 color photos of Siberia trip
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (13): "France trip" (1), 2004 (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS and CD-ROM: One set of ~70 color photos and negatives re: French countryside (6/10/04)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (14): "Barbara Glenn" (2), 2004 (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS and CD-ROM: One set of ~56 color photos and negatives re: Barbara Glenn (11/23/04)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (15): "Barbara Glenn" (2), 2004 (Box 95)
    CD-ROMS: Two CD-ROMS dated 9/29/04 re: travels w/ Barbara
    Removed to Box 106.
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (16): "Siberia" (5), 2004 (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of 14 B&W photos of Siberia trip (11/20/04)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (17): "France trip" (2), 2004 (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~45 B&W photos and negatives re: French countryside (3/11/04)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (18): "France trip" (4), 2004 (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~60 color photos and negatives re: French countryside (6/10/04)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (19): "Barbara Glenn" (3), 2004 (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS and CD-ROM: ~60 color photos re: Barbara Glenn flower arranging, Christmas, SW desert ruins, etc. (3/15/04) (two sets)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (20): "Paris" (2), (2002) (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~60 B&W photos re: procession of priests and nuns in Paris (2002)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (21): "Street Fair", (2004) (Box 95)
    PHOTOGRAPHS and SD CARD: One set of ~70 color photos re: a street fair, plus some Peru shots undated
    SD card removed to Box 106.
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (22): "Paris trip" (3), 2002 (Box 96)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~24 color photos and negatives re: procession of priests and nuns in Paris, book fair, Federica Matta, etc. (5/23/02)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (23), 2003 (Box 96)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~37 color photos and negatives re: SW desert, dogs playing in a hollow log and baseball shots (6/6/2003)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (24): "SW Desert and Barbara", (2004) (Box 96)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~100 color photos (some dupes) re: SW desert trip w/ Barbara Glenn
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (25): "NSM and Family" (3), 2004 (Box 96)
    PHOTOGRAPHS and CD-ROM: One set of ~115 color photos of NSM, Barbara, friends and family (8-23-04)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (26): "Petroglyphs" (2), 2004 (Box 96)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~85 color photos of Southwest desert petroglyph excursion w/ Barbara Glenn (2004)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (27): "Paris trip" (4), 2002 (Box 96)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~24 color photos and negatives re: France
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (28): "Monument Valley", 2004 (Box 96)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~65 color photos and negatives re: Monument Valley, Barbara Glenn, Native American gathering (8/11/04)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (29): "Petroglyphs" (3), 2004 (Box 96)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~115 color photos of Southwest desert petroglyph excursion w/ Barbara Glenn (2004)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (30): "Kachina Doll", undated (Box 96)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~24 B&W photographs and negatives of a Kachina doll on stone steps
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (31): "Balancing Man Nurenberg" 1/3, 2004 (Box 96)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~40 B&W photographs, negatives and contact sheet of Nurenberg, Germany street scenes (9-27-04)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (31): "Balancing Man Nurenberg" 2/3, 2004 (Box 96)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (31): "Balancing Man Nurenberg" 3/3, 2004 (Box 96)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (32): "Barbara & Dolls", 2004 (Box 96)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of ~40 B&W photographs, negatives and contact sheet of Nurenberg, Germany hotel room and dolls (9-27-04)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (1): "Barbara Glenn", undated (Box 97)
    One group of ~30 B&W photographs and negatives of a hotel room, Barbara Glenn, and cityscapes
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (2): "European City", 2006 (Box 97)
    One group of ~20 B&W photographs and negatives of European cityscapes (1/1/06)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (3): "SW Desert", 2006 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of ~17 color photographs of SW desert landscapes (1/6/06)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (4): "Rotterdam, ship, Santa Fe", 2005 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of ~20 B&W photographs and negatives of a European trip ("Rotterdam"), passenger ship and Santa Fe street scenes (12-14-05)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (5): "Barbara Glenn, SW Desert", 2005 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of ~30 B&W photographs and negatives re: SW Desert, Barbara Glenn (11-8-05)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (6): "Barbara Glenn, Durango", 2006 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of ~30 B&W photographs and negatives re: Durango, CO street parade, Barbara Glenn (1-6-06)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (7): "Barbara Glenn, airport, coffee shop...", 2006 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of ~30 B&W photographs and negatives re: Barbara Glenn, airport and coffee shop shots, etc.
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (8): "Mexico", undated (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of ~30 B&W photographs and negatives re: Mazatlan, MEXICO undated
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (9): "Wind Farm", undated (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of ~30 B&W photographs and negatives re: a mountainous wind farm undated
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (10): "NSM Artwork", 2003 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS AND CD-ROM: One group of 79 full color photographs of N. Scott Momaday's paintings (10-25-03)
    CD-ROM removed to Box 107.
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (11): "Siberia", 2008 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS AND CD-ROM: One group of 36 B&W photographs and negatives re: Siberia trip (9/9/08)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (12): "Paris", 2007 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 36 B&W photographs and negatives re: Parisian street scenes (11/20/07)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (13): "Poetry Reading", 2007 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 33 B&W photographs re: mountainous poetry reading/gathering (11/20/07)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (14): "France", 2007 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 33 B&W photographs re: French seaside, unidentified painter (11/20/07)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (15): "France" (2), 2007 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 33 B&W photographs re: Paris scenes (11/20/07)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (16): "France" (3), 2007 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 33 B&W photographs re: France street scenes
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (17): (blurred photos), undated (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 9 B&W blurred photos undated
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (18): "Poetry Reading" (2), 2007 (Box 97)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (19): "Siberia" (2), 2008 (Box 97)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (20): "National Book Festival", 2007 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 36 full-color photographs and negatives re: National Book Festival (Washington, DC) 10/25/07
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (21): "Gettysburg", 2007 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 34 B&W photographs and negatives re: a visit to Gettysburg, PA, 11/20/07
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (22): "Travel", 2007 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 34 B&W miscellaneous travel photos (2007)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (23): "Seals on a Buoy", 2007 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 9 full-color photos of a group of seals on a buoy
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (24): "NYC", 2007 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 30 B&W photographs and negatives re: NYC (blurry) (12-4-07)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (25): "Barbara Glenn", 2007 (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 11 full-color photographs and negatives re: Barbara Glenn (12-4-07)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (26): "Siberia" (3) 1/2, undated (Box 97)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One large group of ~145 faded color photographs and negatives of Russia and Siberia (N. Scott Momaday's first trip there?)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (26): "Siberia" (3) 2/2, undated (Box 97)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (27): "France" (4), (2007) (Box 98)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 47 full-color photographs re: French countryside and Barbara Glenn (in Quaitre Saisons box) undated
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (28): "Horses", 2002 (Box 98)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 37 full-color photographs and negatives re: French horse-riding and clerical event (2002)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (29): (miscellaneous), var. (Box 98)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of mixed B&W and full-color photographs from various times and places (Barbara Glenn, Siberia, Jemez Day School, family, et. al. (in envelope inscribed to Scott and Barbara from Olivier)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (30): "Siberia" (4), undated
    DVD-RWs: Two unmarked discs of ~350 full-color images of Siberia (2007) w/ flash drive
    Removed to Box 107.
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (31): (slides), 2008 (Box 98)
    SLIDES: One set of ~25 slides and image disc (9/6/08)
    Image disc removed to Box 107.
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (32): "Grand Canyon", undated (Box 98)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of 21 full-color photographs of N. Scott Momaday in the Grand Canyon undated
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (33): "Petroglyphs", undated (Box 98)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of 17 full-color photographs of petroglyphs
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (34): Photo Book (1) "Italy", 2004 (Box 98)
    PHOTO BOOK: Small photo book of an Italian trip to Pisa, Assisi, Gubbio w/ Barbara Glenn in 2004
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (35): Photo Book (2) "Barbara Glenn", 2007 (Box 98)
    PHOTO BOOK: Small memorial photo book of Barbara Glenn's life, from childhood through her time with N. Scott Momaday
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (44): "Miscellaneous" (2), 1997-07 (Box 98)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One large group of ~100 miscellaneous color and black and white photos from various travels (1997-2007)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (1): Polaroids, 1979-81 (Box 99)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of 50 color Polaroid photographs of Al and Natachee Momaday and their home (Stonehenge)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (2): "Snapshots", 1973 (Box 99)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of 8 B&W photographs of Al and Natachee Momaday at Arts & Crafts Festival
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (3): "Al Momaday Memorial Exhibition", 1982 (Box 99)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of 13 color Polaroids re: the Al Momaday Memorial Exhibition w/ cover letter dated 2/17/82
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (4): "Ethel Winfield", undated (Box 99)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of 11 color photos re: the death of Natachee Momaday's sister, Ethel Winfield (N. Scott Momaday's aunt) undated
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (5): "Reception for Scott & Regina", 1978 (Box 99)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of 16 color Polaroids re: the reception for N. Scott Momaday and Regina at Stonehenge, August 8, 1978
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (6): "Momaday Artwork and Artifacts", [1978] (Box 99)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of 20 color Polaroids re: antique artifacts, paintings in the Momaday household, taken for insurance purposes
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (7): "Jemez Day School", 1973 (Box 99)
    NEGATIVES: One set of 5 B&W negatives re: Jemez Day School (1973)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (8): "Al Momaday Paintings", [1978] (Box 99)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One set of 8 B&W and one color Polaroid of Al Momaday's paintings
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (9): "Some family snapshots", undated (Box 99)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of four miscellaneous photographs of N. Scott Momaday's daughters and other school snapshots
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (10): Miscellaneous family pictures, 1962-88 (Box 99)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of ~30 miscellaneous B&W and color family photos of Al, Natachee, Scott, plus other family and SW desert scenes (1962-88)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (11): Framed photos, undated (Box 99)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 8 framed family photographs of Natachee and others undated
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (12): "Author Photos", (var.) (Box 99)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One large folder of ~40 author photos of N. Scott Momaday at different points in his literary career, plus negatives (one baby photo!)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (13): "Al Momaday Family Slides", 1975-77 (Box 99)
    SLIDES: Five boxes of Al Momadays' color slides from 1975-77
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (13): "Al Momaday Family Slides", 1975-77 (Box 99)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (14): "Cary and Dixie Dunn", 1988 (Box 99)
    PHOTOGRAPH: One 8"x10" color photo of Cary and Dixie Dunn w/ letter (9/21/88)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (15): "Natachee Artifacts", undated (Box 99)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: One group of 8 full-color photographs of Native American artifacts and clothing in the Momaday collection
  - "African Women Educators Award", 1962 (Box 100)
    MOUNTED PLAQUE: "The the Al Momadays' for Outstanding Work in the Field of Art and Public Relation Awarded by the African Women Educators, 1962"
  - BUSINESS CARDS, 1962 (Box 101)
    One box of Natachee Momaday's business cards undated
  - "Owl in the Cedar Tree", (1976) (Box 99)
    One group of unused dust jackets from the first edition of Natachee Momaday's children's book, "Owl in the Cedar Tree," plus reviews of the reissue (1976)
  - BUSINESS CORRESPONDENCE, (var.) (Box 99)
    One folder of miscellaneous business and personal correspondence to Natachee Momaday, including several letters from the United States Department of the Interior (1967-70)
  - FAMILY WILLS, 1976 (Box 99)
    LEGAL RECORDS: Carbon copies of Alfred M. Momaday and Natachee S. Momaday w/ lawyer's cover letter (5/24/76)
  - PUBLICATIONS, REVIEWS, CLIPPINGS, (var.) (Box 99)
    One large group of miscellaneous publications, reviews and newspaper clippings re: Natachee Momaday and related
  - POSTCARDS, undated (Box 99)
    One miscellaneous group of picture postcards
  - PHOTO ALBUM, 1977 (Box 99)
    One family photo album of Polaroid photographs of Al and Natachee Momaday (1977)
  - ADDRESS BOOK, undated (Box 99)
    Natachee Momaday's personal address book undated
  - "Navaho Nation Fair Award", 1973 (Box 100)
    One Grand Champion Purple Ribbon Award in Fine Arts, Navaho Nation Fair, 1973
  - "Natachee S. Momaday" business plaque, undated (Box 99)
    One orange plaque which reads: "Natachee S. Momaday, Jemez Pueblo, New Mexico 87025"
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (14): "Dallas Johnson", undated (Box 99)
    SLIDES: One orange box of slides of photographs taken by Dallas Johnson of Al Momaday undated
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (15): NSB & Family (slides), (1980) (Box 99)
    SLIDES: One yellow box of slides of NSB family photographs (August, 1980)
  - "Seal of Virginia", (1958) (Box 101)
    One reproduction wall plaque of The Seal of the Council for Virginia 1606-1624; Jamestown Exposition 1607-1957 (1958)
  - SKETCHBOOK (1), undated (Box 100)
    ORIGINAL ARTWORK: One 11"x14" sketchbook of original pastel, pencil and charcoal sketches by Natachee Momaday undated
  - SKETCHBOOK (2), undated (Box 100)
    ORIGINAL ARTWORK: One 11"x14" sketchbook of original pencil sketches and one fully-realized painting of a horseback rider riding into a sunset w/ mesas in the distance undated
  - "Award Ribbons", 1974-78 (Box 101)
    One envelope of various prize ribbons awarded to Al & Natachee Momaday (1974-78)
  - "Al Momaday--Visual Reminders of Faith", 2003 (Box 99)
    One folder of correspondence and materials re: Al Momaday's art in the St. Luke Lutheran Church, Albuquerque NM (2/4/03)
  - PHOTOGRAPH (16): "Al and Natachee Momaday", undated (Box 100)
    One mounted 8"x10" B&W photograph of Al and Natachee Momaday in their Native American arts booth undated
  - PHOTOGRAPH (1): "NSM High School Photo", (1952) (Box 102)